Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The cluster of colonies furthest from Earth, known as Side 3...
...proclaimed themselves the Principality of Zeon.
And launched a war of independence against the Earth Federation.
In roughly one month of fighting, the Principality of Zeon...
...and the Federation Forces caused the deaths of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
The war became a stalemate, and eight months have now passed.
Gundam Rising!!
Slender, you stay here.
Yes, Chief.
The military facilities appear to be in the upper right block, sir.
This should be rush hour, but I only see one car.
Not a person in sight.
Wait! There's a child!
Amuro!
Amuro?
What? He hasn't even eaten yet.
Amuro?!
I thought I'd find you cooped up in here.
You've got to eat your breakfast... You should take better care of your health!
Hello, Amuro. Hello, Amuro.
You're full of energy as always, Haro.
Thank you, Amuro.
What were you planning on wearing today?
Amuro?
I'll eat after I finish rewiring this computer.
Didn't you hear the evacuation order?
Evacuation order?
Is that what the siren was?
Give me a break!
Didn't you listen to the military broadcast?
A warship's docking so we have to evacuate.
Why?
I don't know.
Amuro, we don't have time!
All right.
Evacuate at once!
I'll wait outside. Come on, Haro.
All right already...
Hayato!
Hi, Fraw Bow!
Hey! You're Amuro's closest neighbor! It was your responsibility to tell him.
Oh, about the evacuation?
Of course. He's all alone, you know.
Well, if military engineers like his dad hadn't moved here in the first place, we...
Are you still bitter about them moving us to make way for their research facility?
It's not like that...
Hayato!
Coming! Bye...
Amuro!
Amuro, it's bad manners to eat and drive.
Isn't your father on the incoming ship?
I think so. He said he was going Earthside about a week ago.
Do you think they'll be fighting here?
I don't know. He wouldn't tell me anything.
Get the Gundam components loaded onto the White Base.
Speed up the ground operations.
Yes sir!
Damn the White Base! They're leading a Zeon ship here!
So this is it?
Yes, sir.
The Federation has a fine new battleship.
With this new ship, and the completed Gundam...
...we'll have no trouble crushing Zeon!
Excuse me, Lieutenant Ray. We're docking at Side 7 now.
Please report to the bridge at once.
Very well.
Your name is Bright, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
How many months in the military?
Six months, sir.
And you're 19 years old, correct?
Yes, sir.
When we start mass-producing the Gundam...
...we may be able to end this war without sending kids like you into battle.
Is that your son, sir?
Yes.
I hear there are kids his age fighting as guerrilla soldiers.
Is it true?
Yes, I'm told that it happens.
How terrible.
Thank you for coming, Lieutenant Ray.
So we weren't able to outrun that Zeon ship.
Unfortunately, no.
It seems I don't have much luck.
To run into a prize like that on my way home from a mission.
Maybe they were the lucky ones.
Yes, Lt. Commander Char. But...
Could the Federation's Operation V really be based in a remote Side like this one?
They do.
They could be developing a more advanced mobile suit than our Zakus.
No way. Not in such a remote place.
They're late.
It's coming in.
It's Code CC2.
See? Exactly as I predicted.
You mean the Federation has mobile suits?
We should assume their development was successful.
The third one's a mobile suit as well.
There could be more in there.
This could be our only chance.
We're just here on recon.
But if they get those mobile suits loaded onto that battleship...!
Don't be hasty to seek your glory.
Gene, what are you doing?!
Look at Lt. Commander Char...
...he built his career on actual combat!
Hey, Gene wait?!
Do you realize this is insubordination?! Cease and desist, Gene!
Who's going to care, after I pull this off.
The sooner you defeat the enemy, the better.
That's close.
Maybe it's an asteroid.
The way these tremors are traveling, they must be caused by...
Explosions!
It's Zeon. A Zeon attack.
Amuro!
I'll go find my father.
Amuro, no!
Hey! Going out could put us all in danger.
My father's with the military. A shelter like this won't survive...
I'm going to request an evacuation to the ship that just docked today.
Wait!
Stop it!
Please close the other door.
A Zeon mobile suit...
So this is a Zeon Zaku?
Hey! Civilians must remain in the shelter!
I'm looking for an engineering officer named Tem Ray. Where is he?
Probably on the ship...
Unload it.
Look out!
They're dead...
"Classified Materials"?
Th-This must be... the Federation's mobile suit.
Mobile Suit
I was following orders, but...
Where's Chief Denim?
Sir!
He's moved forward, to support Gene.
And the Federation has mobile suits there?
Yes, sir.
Slender, take as many pictures as you can... and retreat if it becomes dangerous.
Yes, sir!
What'll we do?
I'm surprised that Denim couldn't control a rookie.
I may have to go out there myself.
Take us closer to Side 7.
Yes, sir!
Get to the space port! Hurry!
- Faster!
- Run!
Computer-controlled operation...
A learning type computer...?
Wow! No wonder Dad's been preoccupied...
Amuro!
Amuro! What are you doing?!
Damn you!
Amuro...
Amuro!
Use one of the inner lifts for this.
Fraw Bow, get to the space port!
Amuro!
Fraw! Hurry up!
Okay!
Dad!
What about Lift #3?
It's being used!
Dad!
The Gundam must go before the evacuees.
Take it up to the White Base and prepare it for battle.
Yes, sir!
Dad!
Amuro, why aren't you evacuating?
Dad, are mobile suits more important to you than human beings?
Move it out.
Dad!
Get up to the White Base, quickly.
The White Base?
It's the warship that's in port.
What's taking so long?
The engine won't start!
Go to the White Base. I'll go find a tractor.
But Dad!
So, this is the Federation's secret weapon.
Amuro! Hurry!
Are you all right, Amuro?!
Fraw Bow!
Fraw... Fraw Bow!
Fraw Bow, don't give up!
Amuro.
Can you stand up?
M-Mother?
Grandpa?
Mother? Mother?
Mother!
Fraw, they'll get you too. You've gotta go.
No!
Get a hold of yourself! You're stronger than this!
Make a run for the space port.
You can do it, right, Fraw Bow?
I'll be there soon. Now, go!
Run, Fraw Bow!
Run, Fraw...
That's it, Fraw Bow...
Way to go...
This will work...
Exactly the same. Is this it...?
Incredible!
The energy gain is more than five times!
Let's give it a try.
Is that it?
Here it is.
Can I make it in time?
Left... and right.
Hurry! Get the weapons!
White Base! Can't you launch a Core Fighter?
Impossible!
Not unless we blast open the Side's hull!
Have we deployed all combat personnel?!
Yes, sir! And we've also sent pilots to retrieve the Gundam.
We never expected an attack from within the colony.
Rise!
H-He's right in front of me!
Uh... weapons...
Chief Denim!
The enemy's mobile suit has moved!
What?!
I thought they were all just unassembled parts!
But it's not functioning very well. I'll take care of it.
Here it comes!
This mobile suit is unbelievable!
The rifles are useless.
Just watch, you damn Zaku!
We're just on a recon mission! Retreat, Gene!
What are you saying?! If we don't get him now, the enemy will...
It's standing!
Please, get up!
Get up!
There we go.
Sir, one of our mobile suits is operating!
What?
What kind of attack is that?! Who's in the cockpit?
Oh no... I'm out of ammo!
I'll get you! No matter how thick your armor is...
He's coming!
It's like the mobile suit's shaking in terror!
So that's the power of the Federation's mobile suit!
A-Amazing...
You're not getting away!
Doesn't this thing have any other weapons?
Is this it?
Gene, can you jump to where Slender is?
I'll use the back-up camera. I can see.
I'm going to jump!
I won't let you get away!
If I hit the mobile suit's engine, it might destroy all of Side 7.
What... What should I do?
You'll pay for what you did to Gene!
What to do... Can I target just the cockpit?
If this Zaku blows up, all the air in Side 7 will be sucked out!
Rush the civilians onto the White Base.
Yes, sir!
I don't think any more air is escaping.
And the transfer of the Gundam?
All the regular engineers were killed.
We'll have him do it
Huh?
Whether he's a real pilot or not...
...we need his help.
What is it?
Where's Slender?
He's escaped Side 7 and is headed this way.
No one likes to admit to them.
To the mistakes they've made because of their youth.
As Char waits for the White Base to escape from Side 7...
...he shows his true power as the Red Comet, and faces Gundam with brutal force.
For both Char and Amuro...
...this battle reveals a ferocity that neither has experienced before.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Destroy Gundam.
Next Time
Destroy Gundam!
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...